twas ten to midnight on December 24th
and all was not well in the far far
north some little elves were wrapping a
thousand and 24 toys rollerskates for a
thousand and 24 good girls and boys at
ten to midnight the elves call Saint
Nick tonight all the boxes had been
filled extra quick st. Nick was thrilled
right then fill up the sleigh a thousand
twenty four boxes and we're on our way
then mrs. Christmas burst through the
doors
where are your dirty socks Santa Claus
the young elf cried Santa I'll drop your
dirty socks --is in one of the thousand
and twenty four boxes quick unwrap every
single box
I'm not leaving till you find those
socks sorry Santa said the supervisor
elf those workers are all Union and we
finish at twelve said Santa no need to
be unpleasant I've got a big pair of
scales just weigh each present they're
always the same when you put them in
each bucket except for one and that
one's the culprit with all due respect
reply the supervisor elf
it'll take a jolly long time and you can
do it yourself if we could make one
comparison every second will be here
till 12:00 all seven a little elf part
up I've got an idea we just need to use
dividing conquer here put half the boxes
on that scale and half the boxes on this
whichever side goes up that pile we
dismiss the supervisor elf with an
unimpressed gaze pointed out we'll still
be here four days you've narrowed it
down to 512 hardly any help from this
little elf white said the elf
only beginning his campaign watch what
happens when we are verdict gained so
they have did
and now their fix was narrowed to 256
then after the third comparison of
weight their problem was reduced to 128
then 64 10 32 16 8 4 2 it's true
on the tenth comparison was much joy
this elf had found the erroneous toy a
job that could have gone well beyond the
time limits took just a matter of
minutes so the gift was replaced the
elves went home and Santa was set for
his worldwide roam no poor child far or
near will have to smell Santa's dirty
underwear but first the little elf was
approached by Saint Nick where did you
learn your clever trick a little elf
replied on magic
I make no reliance all I need to use is
a little computer science
[Music]